Justin Velander Holt

3735 West Diversey Avenue #2F · Chicago, IL 60647 312-568-6632 · <u>justin@onthecodeagain.com</u>

onthecodeagain.com

linkedin.com/in/velander

github.com/justinvholt

COVER LETTER

Dear Hiring Manager,

For the past five years I literally donated my body to science for the purpose of getting out of debt and saving up tuition to acquire a new skill set. I crisscrossed the country countless times in pursuit of clinical trials. I navigated my way through downpours and blizzards, spin outs and wrecks, professional rejection and personal heartbreak. All-too-frequent 21+ hour drives. 250+ days per year in a controlled environment doing not-so-hard time. (Think of living in a dorm with labs attached.) Thousands of blood draws for the hope of medical breakthroughs and a sizable nest egg.

Simply, it's a been a bizarre and contentious journey to even begin learning code.

But learn code I did. After two years of online tutorials, one-on-one mentoring, a handful of open-source projects and a 9-week intensive boot camp in Rio de Janeiro, I am certainly ready to launch a career as a full stack developer. I've done a lot of growing on my own, but now I'm seeking a team to take me beyond the tinkering stage and keep me on the right path. I'm seeking secure employment and glowing references, and I'm determined to put in the due diligence to earn both. I intend to bridge this gap between learning and doing by giving my focus and dedication to those who will take a chance on me.

I've worked so hard just to get here. I'm looking forward to traveling farther, working smarter, living brighter - and to no longer be doing it alone.

Quo imus, Justin Holt

Justin Velander Holt

3735 West Diversey Avenue #2F · Chicago, IL 60647 312-568-6632 · <u>justin@onthecodeagain.com</u>

onthecodeagain.com

linkedin.com/in/velander

github.com/justinvholt

SKILLS

RubyHTML

• Ruby on Rails

PythonJavascript

SQLReactJS

JavajQuery

Bootstrap

CSSLinux

• Github

• Heroku

EXPERIENCE

OnTheCodeAgain.com

Freelance Full Stack Developer

December 2017 -

Present

 Freelance/open-source web development utilizing Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, Java, JavaScript, jQuery, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and SQL, Notable projects include:

- i.) Chronos Automated laytime management system; built with Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails
- ii.) dopcast Comprehensive podcast search engine; built with Ruby and Ruby on Rails
- iii.) On the Code Again Personal web site portfolio; built with Ruby, jQuery and Ruby on Rails
- iv.) BFN Networks Podcast network site; built with Wordpress, HTML and CSS

Auditor - Phase I Medical Trials

Auditor (Contract)

March 2016 -

Present

• Collating and organizing paperwork for individual Phase I medical trials for facilities nationwide, ensuring accuracy and compliance per pharmaceutical drug sponsors' guidelines

Freelance Editor/Copywriter

Editor · Copywriter

Chicago, IL

May 2013 -

January 2018

• Short-term and per diem assignments writing, proofreading, editing and critiquing media mail, brochures, advertisements, essays, blogs and manuscripts

BMO Capital Markets

File Clerk - Trust & Operations

Chicago, IL

Chicago, IL

February 2012 -

May 2013

- Reorganizing paper filing systems of Trust & Operations in preparation of upcoming audits
- · Converting paper filing systems to digital archive

Last Temptation of Clarence Odbody: A Novel, The Chicago, IL

Creative Consultant · Editor

October 2010 –

August 2011

- Intensive editorial work on 223-page manuscript for Chicago novelist John Pierson focusing on narration/POV, structure, plot, character development, dialogue, continuity, rhetoric and rewrites
- Acting as creative consultant for additional scenes/dialogue that help further story and strengthen underlying themes

Citadel Investment Group

March 2007 – November 2009

Data Entry Specialist · Database Management

Editing, updating and maintaining Securitized Products Group (SPG) database

- Analyzing mortgage prospectuses and pooling and servicing agreements to extract relevant information.
- Processing daily bid/offer lists and monthly remittance reports into specialized MS Excel database to be used as reference guide by global network of financial analysts
- De facto team leader regarding continuity within databases as well as discussions with programmers and supervisors on how data systems could be streamlined for easier access

Sprint Nextel Reston, VA July 2006 -Data Entry Specialist October 2006

Sorting and filing two separate directories into one integrated system for insurance division

- Transferring contact information for 10.000+ business clients from paper contracts to intranet database
- Supervisor of five employees for the purpose of ensuring continuity for both paper and digital registries

Clio Awards Chicago, IL January 2000 -June 2006

Administrative Assistant · Database Editor

- · Assisting with data entry, filing, proofreading, sorting mail and answering phones for international advertising awards show
- Maintaining and supervising Client and Entries databases (approx. 12,000 names and 13,000 annual submissions, respectively)
- Editing and revising final proofs of Shortlist and Winners books (approx. 300 pages each)
- Acting Supervisor of Clio Festival Registration: greeting and registering 1200+ attendees; maintaining guest lists for gala events; customer service; handling payments; sorting gift bags; arranging signage; organizing displays and supervising student volunteers throughout week-long festival in Miami

EDUCATION

Le Wagon Rio de Janeiro, BR October 2018 -Intensive Coding Boot Camp December 2018

- 9-week intensive coding boot camp specializing in full stack development Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Javascript, iQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Linux, Github and Heroku
- Team lead and demo presenter for capstone project: https://youtu.be/W0UOC5IJ4wo?t=400

ENTREPRENEURIAL

The Penguin's Tuxedo Chicago, IL August 2008 -Founder · Lead Organizer Present

- Founder and lead organizer for not-for-profit event promotions platform that specializes in outings to cultural events/productions at discount rates to subscribers
- Networking with artists, venues, managers and publicists to coordinate group rates and incentives

Justin Holt - Voice Over Chicago, IL February 2005 –

Voice Over Artist Present

BFN Networks (BFNinYourEars.net) Chicago, IL February 2000 -Founder · Producer · Music Promoter June 2014

- Founder and producer of BFN Networks podcasting station and host of weekly podcasts Noble Efforts, The Sound Of You & Me, Secondhand Neon and Bring Back The DJ
- Editing and mastering episodes, skits and interviews for web streaming/podcasting
- Writing copy for all episode guides and interview summaries
- Networking with artists, management, publicists and label reps for the purpose of discovering new music and scheduling band interviews
- Comprehensive web site building and maintenance (Wordpress/HTML/CSS)